ceruleanstudios.com 2011-08-28

# Cerulean Studios' Privacy Policy

Cerulean Studios is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy policy applies to data collected by Cerulean Studios through its websites that link to this privacy policy, the Trillian™ software (including Trillian™ for Windows and Trillian™ for Mac (together, "Trillian™"), and Trillian™ for iPhone, Trillian™ for Android, Trillian™ for BlackBerry, and Trillian™ for Web (together, "Trillian™ for Mobile Devices")), and other software and services that may be provided by Cerulean Studios from time to time (the "Cerulean Services"). This privacy policy does not apply to information collected by websites, software, services, plugins, or features provided by third parties (the "Third Party Services") and accessible through the Cerulean Services or otherwise. Please contact the providers of the Third Party Services if you have questions about their privacy policies.

### THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

You are not required to provide personally identifiable information to visit Cerulean Studios' websites. However, you will be required to provide certain personally identifiable information in order to establish an account with Cerulean Studios or make use of certain Cerulean Services. 

#### General Information

Cerulean Studios may ask you to provide personally identifiable information (for example, your email address, mailing address, telephone number, or instant messenger account names) in order to access and use certain Cerulean Services. In addition, third party communications networks may provide Cerulean Studios with information about you when you connect to them using Cerulean Services. If you choose to purchase a paid Cerulean Service such as Trillian™ Pro, Cerulean Studios may ask you to provide additional information (depending on your purchase method; for example, your credit card information and billing address) which will be used to complete your purchase. 

####  Usage Statistics 

Cerulean Studios may collect information that you make available when you interact with the Cerulean Services. This information may include the pages you view on Cerulean Studios' websites, website and instant messenger traffic analysis data used to optimize the Cerulean Services, crash reports from the Trillian™ software, and technical information such as your browser's window dimensions, your operating system, and the time you spend viewing a web page. Cerulean Studios may also collect certain commonly available information that your browser provides to every website that you visit. This information includes your Internet Protocol (IP) address, the web page you have requested, the referring website (including search engines), your browser software, your browser's language settings, and access time and date. Cerulean Studios may also use "cookies" and other similar technology in connection with the Cerulean Services, as discussed in the cookie section below. 

####  User Account Information 

In order to access the Cerulean Services, Cerulean Studios requires that you create a unique username and password (a "Trillian Account"). In association with your Trillian Account, we will store any demographic or other personal information (for example, your gender and age) you choose to provide to us for the purpose of creating a user profile ("User Profile Information"). We may display the User Profile Information that you choose to provide to us on your public user profile web page. 

#### Instant Messenger Usernames and Passwords

At your option, you may request that Cerulean Studios store certain third-party network account information (encrypted usernames and passwords) on its servers ("Third-Party Account Information"). This encrypted information is only accessible by you and cannot be read by third parties, including Cerulean Studios employees. You can learn more about Cerulean Studios' security practices at http://www.trillian.im/security/. If you choose to disable the storage of Third-Party Account Information, Third-Party Account Information will only be stored on the computer(s) on which Trillian™ is installed. 

#### Instant Messenger Contact Lists

Cerulean Studios may store your instant messenger contact lists (the "User Contact Lists") on its servers. The User Contact Lists stored on Cerulean Studios' servers contain certain information provided by each instant messaging provider (including contact names and display names, group names, and contact "notes") and are not encrypted. The User Contact Lists are only available to the Trillian Account that uploads them. 

#### Instant Messenger Conversations 

When installed and used on your computer, Trillian™ connects directly to various third party communications networks. Your communications using those networks are governed by their respective privacy policies. At your option, you may request that Trillian™ store your conversations in logs on your computer so that you may review past conversations.

Certain Trillian™ software will offer you the option to upload your conversation logs to Cerulean Studios' servers so that you can access your logs using Trillian™ software on multiple devices or platforms. Conversation logs are not encrypted. The transmission of conversation logs to and from Cerulean Studios' servers is protected with industry standard encryption, such as the Transport Layer Security (TLS) protocol. Conversation logs that are uploaded to Cerulean Studios' servers are only available to the Trillian Account that uploads them. Cerulean Studios makes no warranty regarding the availability of conversation logs uploaded to Cerulean Studios' servers. You are solely responsible for the content of your conversation logs.

Trillian™ for Mobile Devices operates by establishing connections to Cerulean Studios' servers. In order to provide services through Trillian™ for Mobile Devices, Cerulean Studios may temporarily store recent instant messenger session information and conversations of users of Trillian™ for Mobile Devices ("User Messaging Information"). This information is stored only for the purpose of transmitting the information back to you (e.g., to reliably deliver messages to a mobile device that temporarily loses internet connectivity, or to provide you with a reminder excerpt of your last conversation) and is not permanently archived unless requested by you as a part of the conversation logging feature. The User Messaging Information is only available to the Trillian Account associated with it.

Trillian™ will not otherwise transmit, store, or access the content of your conversations, except as required in order to comply with law, rule or regulation. Please review the Trillian™ documentation to learn more about logging features provided by Trillian™ 

### HOW YOUR INFORMATION IS PROTECTED 

Cerulean Studios is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number or password) over the Internet, we protect it with industry standard encryption, such as the Transport Layer Security (TLS) protocol. Any credit card information that you provide to us is either encrypted or limited to the first 3 and last 5 digits when stored.

If a password is used to help protect your accounts and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users. Cerulean Studios employees will never ask you for your password. If you become aware of any unauthorized disclosure of you account or personal information, please notify Cerulean Studios and promptly change your password to prevent unauthorized access and use of your account. 

### HOW YOUR INFORMATION IS USED 

#### Enabling Certain Cerulean Services 

Certain Cerulean Services will not function unless you provide Cerulean Studios with certain personally identifiable information. For example, the Cerulean Services cannot connect to a third party communications network unless you provide Cerulean Studios with certain required login information (such as your username, password, and any other required information by such network) (the "User Access Information") and you permit Cerulean Studios to share the User Access Information. By providing the User Access Information to Cerulean Studios and accessing and using the Cerulean Services, you authorize us to share the User Access Information with the relevant third party communications network provider solely for the purpose of establishing and authenticating your session. 

#### Improving Cerulean Services 

Cerulean Studios collects and uses your personal information to operate and improve its websites and the other Cerulean Services. These uses may include providing you with more effective customer service; making the Cerulean Studios websites and other Cerulean Services easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information; performing research and analysis aimed at improving Cerulean Studios products, services and technologies; and permitting you to gain access to certain features of the Cerulean Services not available to the general public (including your user account information and preferences). 

#### Sending Authorized Communications to You 

Cerulean Studios may also use your personal information to communicate with you, including sending certain mandatory service communications such as welcome letters, billing reminders, information on technical service issues, and security announcements. In addition, Cerulean Studios may send periodic member letters that are considered part of the Cerulean Services. Cerulean Studios may also occasionally send you product surveys or promotional mailings to inform you of other products or services available from Cerulean Studios. You may opt out of promotional mailings and surveys from Cerulean Studios by disabling receipt of these items in your user account preferences. 

#### Enabling Plugins and Other Third-Party Enhancements to Cerulean Services 

Cerulean Studios may make personally identifiable information about you available to software applications developed by third parties making use of the plugin development architecture provided by Cerulean Studios. This information will be limited to the information required by the plugin in order to operate correctly. Certain plugins may also collect personally identifiable information in addition to the information described in this privacy policy. The use of your personally identifiable information provided to plugins by the Cerulean Services or collected by the plugins is governed by the privacy policy of the applicable software developer. Please review the privacy policy for each plugin before making use of the plugin software. 

#### Storage of Your Personal Information 

Personal information collected on Cerulean Studios websites and through the Cerulean Services may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Cerulean Studios or service providers maintain facilities. Personally identifiable information may be transferred across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world in connection with the Cerulean Services. 

#### Disclosure of Your Personal Information to Third Parties 

Except as described in this privacy policy, Cerulean Studios will not disclose your personal information to third parties without your consent. Cerulean Studios does not sell, lease, or rent your email address or contact information to third parties. 

#### Miscellaneous Issues 

Cerulean Studios may hire other companies to provide limited services on its behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings, hosting websites, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of Cerulean Services. Those service providers will be permitted to obtain only the personal information they need to deliver such services, are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information, and are prohibited from using it for any other purpose. Additionally, for credit card processing, our fraud detection vendors may use aggregate data to improve their ability to detect fraudulent uses of credit cards. 

Cerulean Studios may access or disclose information about you, including the content of your communications, in order to: (a) comply with the law or respond to lawful requests or legal process; (b) protect the rights or property of Cerulean Studios or our customers, including the enforcement of our agreements or policies governing your use of the Cerulean Services; or (c) act on a good faith belief that such access or disclosure is necessary to protect the personal safety of Cerulean Studios employees, customers or the public. 

In the event that Cerulean Studios is acquired by or merges with another company or transfers substantially all of its assets to another company, Cerulean Studios may transfer all of its user information and data, including information about you (including personally identifiable information), to that other company. 

### THIRD PARTY ADVERTISEMENTS 

Advertisements displayed on Cerulean Studios' products, services, and websites may be delivered via an advertising management service. When you use a product or view a web page on our website that contains advertising provided by one of our advertising management services, the advertising service company may place a cookie on or retrieve a cookie from your computer if you have enabled cookies. This cookie may uniquely designate your computer and web browser, without containing any personally identifying information such as your name or e-mail address. Advertisements may also make use of "trackers" or "web beacons" to collect statistical information regarding the advertisements. Cerulean Studios will not sell, assign, or otherwise transfer your personally identifiable information to any advertising management service. 

### COOKIES AND OTHER SIMILAR TECHNOLOGY 

Cerulean Studios may use "cookies" to personalize your experience of its websites. A cookie is a small text file that Internet browsers may place on your computer's hard drive. Cookies contain information that a website server is able to read when you visit that website. 

#### Cookie Usage 

Cerulean Studios may use cookies to store your preferences and other information on your computer in order to save you time by eliminating the need to repeatedly enter the same information when you visit Cerulean Studios websites. Cookies allow Cerulean Studios to display your personalized content on your later visits to these websites. 

When you sign in to a Cerulean Studios website using your Trillian Account, Cerulean Studios stores your unique session information in an encrypted cookie on your hard disk. This cookie allows you to move from page to page on the site without having to sign in again on each page. When you log out of a Cerulean Studios website (or if 1 hour has passed since your last visit), this cookie is deleted from your computer or otherwise expired. 

#### Cookie Control 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use other interactive features of the Cerulean Studios websites and the Cerulean Services that depend on cookies. Please review your browser's documentation if you would like to disable or reject cookies. 

If you choose to accept cookies, you also have the ability to later delete cookies that you have accepted. Please refer to your browser's documentation if you would like to delete cookies. If you choose to delete cookies, any settings and preferences controlled by those cookies will be deleted and may need to be recreated. 

#### Web Beacons and Usage 

In addition, Cerulean Studios websites, email correspondence, and other communications may contain "web beacons", "single-pixel GIFs", "tracking images", or other similar technology. These files are small, transparent images provided by Cerulean Studios or third party website statistics software and are used solely to facilitate the collection of non-personally identifiable information about your use of Cerulean Services, including the number of website visitors Cerulean Studios receives, the number of times an email from Cerulean Studios is opened, and other similar uses. 

### CHILDREN UNDER AGE 13 

Children under 13 are not permitted to register with Cerulean Studios or use Cerulean Services. 

### CONTACTING CERULEAN STUDIOS 

Cerulean Studios welcomes your comments and questions regarding this privacy policy, including any questions you may have about the particular use of your information. If you would like to contact us regarding this privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at customer-service@ceruleanstudios.com. 

### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY 

Cerulean studios may update this privacy policy from time to time to reflect changes in the Cerulean Services and customer feedback. When we post changes to this privacy policy, we will revise the "last updated" date at the bottom of this privacy policy. If there are material changes to this privacy policy or in how Cerulean Studios will use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes on our website prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy policy to stay informed of how Cerulean Studios is protecting your information. If you disagree with the changes to this privacy policy, you may choose to opt out by sending written notice to customer-service@ceruleanstudios.com requesting termination of your account. 

_Last Updated: May 2nd, 2011_
